<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>https://bitsofsteve.com/</id><title>Stephen Gabriel</title><subtitle>Blog and portfolio focused on Kubernetes, Docker, Containers, DevOps, Reliability, Databases, Linux Cloud services and other technical content. Philosophy, life lessons, and personal growth.</subtitle> <updated>2025-10-19T02:23:03+01:00</updated> <author> <name>Stephen Gabriel</name> <uri>https://bitsofsteve.com/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://bitsofsteve.com/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" href="https://bitsofsteve.com/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2025 Stephen Gabriel </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>Thank You, Internet Stranger</title><link href="https://bitsofsteve.com/posts/thank-you-internet-stranger/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thank You, Internet Stranger" /><published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2025-10-19T02:22:38+01:00</updated> <id>https://bitsofsteve.com/posts/thank-you-internet-stranger/</id> <content src="https://bitsofsteve.com/posts/thank-you-internet-stranger/" /> <author> <name>Stephen Gabriel</name> </author> <category term="Blog" /> <summary> For centuries, philosophers have wrestled with a question that seems simple but refuses to stay still: Can we prove that human goodness is real? Not just situationally useful, not just socially conditioned, but fundamentally, essentially real? Jung gave us the collective unconscious. That deep reservoir of shared human experience, the archetypal patterns that connect us across time and culture... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>The Day Everybody Stopped Commenting</title><link href="https://bitsofsteve.com/posts/the-day-we-all-stopped/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Day Everybody Stopped Commenting" /><published>2025-08-30T00:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2025-08-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated> <id>https://bitsofsteve.com/posts/the-day-we-all-stopped/</id> <content src="https://bitsofsteve.com/posts/the-day-we-all-stopped/" /> <author> <name>Stephen Gabriel</name> </author> <category term="Blog" /> <summary> One morning, everybody stopped commenting. Nothing extraordinary had happened. The week before, the month before dead air. No bombs, no breaking news demanding our outrage. Just normal. Perversely normal. Kids readied for school. Markets opened. The Stock Exchange buzzed. Everything moved as it always moved. But we had already been dying. Not the acute kind that announces itself the chronic ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>The Imperative for Healthcare-Specific Databases; Enhancing Data Management and Patient Care</title><link href="https://bitsofsteve.com/posts/healthcare-database/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Imperative for Healthcare-Specific Databases; Enhancing Data Management and Patient Care" /><published>2021-05-31T00:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2021-05-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated> <id>https://bitsofsteve.com/posts/healthcare-database/</id> <content src="https://bitsofsteve.com/posts/healthcare-database/" /> <author> <name>Stephen Gabriel</name> </author> <category term="Blog" /> <summary> Introduction The healthcare sector must deal with the difficulty of managing massive amounts of sensitive and complicated data. Traditional database management tools have failed to meet the specific requirements of the healthcare industry, leading to inefficiencies and even threats to patient safety. This article argues that the healthcare industry would benefit from the creation of specialize... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>AWS VPC Fundamentals; A Playful Exploration of Virtual Private Clouds</title><link href="https://bitsofsteve.com/posts/aws-vpc-play/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AWS VPC Fundamentals; A Playful Exploration of Virtual Private Clouds" /><published>2021-03-20T00:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2021-03-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated> <id>https://bitsofsteve.com/posts/aws-vpc-play/</id> <content src="https://bitsofsteve.com/posts/aws-vpc-play/" /> <author> <name>Stephen Gabriel</name> </author> <category term="Blog" /> <summary> Introduction Welcome to the whimsical world of AWS VPC, where we will embark on a delightful journey to understand the fundamentals of Virtual Private Clouds. With playful diagrams and straightforward explanations, we will simplify the complex concepts of AWS VPC, making it a breeze for you to grasp and apply this powerful tool. What is AWS VPC? Picture AWS VPC (Virtual Private Cloud) as you... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>A Kubernetes Poem</title><link href="https://bitsofsteve.com/posts/k8s-poem/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Kubernetes Poem" /><published>2021-01-20T00:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2021-01-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated> <id>https://bitsofsteve.com/posts/k8s-poem/</id> <content src="https://bitsofsteve.com/posts/k8s-poem/" /> <author> <name>Stephen Gabriel</name> </author> <category term="Blog" /> <summary> Gather ‘round, young friends, and hear, A story about Kubernetes, so clear, A tale that’s fun and easy to grasp, In a simple poem, you’ll soon clasp. Imagine a harbor full of ships, Each carrying cargo on many trips, The harbor master, strong and wise, Keeps things organized, no surprise. Now think of computers, big and small, Working together, answering every call, To store data and run code... </summary> </entry> </feed>
